# YIFAN LIAO

Research Interests: Al4security & ADS testing

personal web

✓ lyf1998118@gmail.com

**\** +86 17754927977

github

• Chongging, China

in Linkedin

BIO -

I'm a research assistant at NUS Research Institute in Chongging, where I am supervised by Prof. Zhiyong Huang. I obtained my M.Comp. in Artificial Intelligence at National University of Singapore (NUS). Before Joining NUS, I received my B.Eng. in Mechanical Engineering at Chongqing University (CQU) in 2021.

**SKILLS** 

Languages: Python, JavaScript, Java, HTML.

Technologies: Linux, Docker, Kubernetes.

#### PROJECTS

Web Security Role: Leader

# **Detect and Explaining Tamper-based attacks**

Still reviewing

This project detects and explains attack-induced anomalies in web applications by learning behavioral normalities during runtime, modeling them with first-order logic, and generating executable Python scripts, leveraging LLMs in the learning process to enhance detection and explanation.

**Cyber Security** Role: Participants Learning Verifiable Invariant to Detect Evasive Intrusion Attacks (Leader: Dr. Ming Xu) Still reviewing This project addresses the pressing concern of Advanced Persistent Threat (APT) attacks by proposing Refuter, an advanced intrusion detection technique. Refuter identifies disguising processes in APT attacks by leveraging emerging language models' agents to construct normal behavioral invariants of system processes. It raises intrusion alarms based on inconsistencies between a target program's behaviors and its claimed process intentions.

**ADS Testing** Role: Leader

Boost the Fuzzers of ADS through Explanation-driven and Diversity-enhancing Project Webpage

This project addresses the need for a diversity-driven and explanation-oriented solution by introducing DivX, which enhances existing ADS fuzzers. It achieves this by discovering diversified failures across different driving scenarios and deriving actionable explanations. These explanations help summarize failure patterns, generate test cases, and provide runtime remedies to avoid potential accidents.

### EDUCATION

Master, National University of Singapore (Supervisor: Prof. JS Dong) 9/2021 - 6/2023

Artificial Intelligence

Thesis: Boost the Fuzzers of ADS through Explanation-driven and Diversity-enhancing

GPA: 3.5/5

Visiting student, University of Cincinnati 6/2020 - 6/2021

Mechanical Engineer

GPA: 3.67/4

**Bachelor, Chongging University** 9/2016 - 6/2021

GPA: 3.38/4

Mechanical Engineer

## **EXPERIENCE**

## 6/2023 - 6/2024 Research Assistant (P.I: Prof.Yang Liu)

Singapore Govtech

- · Lead a web security project, developing a comprehensive end-to-end web tamper detection toolset.
- · Assisted in a system log detection project by building the evaluation platform through investigating and running log detection algorithms (DeepLog, LogAnomaly, Logrobust, etc.) and several CVE PoCs. Web Security / LLM for Security / Log Detection

## 12/2022 - 6/2023 Research Intern (P.I: Dr. Hoon Wei Lim)

NCS Group (Singtel's Subsidiary)

· Assist in a cyber security project by participating in experimental deployment through researching and running APT29 attacks, as well as running tasks involving disguising processes. APT Attack Detection / LLM for Security

12/2019 - 6/2020 Robotics Intern

Chongqing Kaibao Robotic Company

· Apply the extended Kalman filter to obtain accurate sensor data for robot navigation Robotics / Matlab

**SERVICES** 

PRDC 2023 (Chair: Prof.JS Dong) - Program Committee

LANGUAGES

English - Fluent, Chinese - Native